Elsewhere in the course, we saw the pass keyword
and its use as a placeholder within code. We used
pass within the context of a loop. Now, we
want to know how pass is used in the context
of a function. We also want to see what an output
screen shows when pass is used within a function.
The eventual goal of this code example, 425-pass,
is to calculate the total amount for a car,
given its amount, the licensing fee,
and all applicable taxes. As of now,
we do not know what the proper formula is for
calculating the total car amount. However,
on lines 1 and 2, we have the calculate total
function with the pass keyword. In this context,
the pass keyword is being used as a placeholder
for future code. We can wait for the information
or calculations needed to finish creating the
calculate_total function. The get amounts function
starts on line 4 and, on lines 5 and 6, gathers
input for a car amount and a license amount and
converts those entries to integers so that they
can be used in calculations. Then, on line 7,
the total is rendered in a print statement. The
amount is printed on line 8. And the get_amounts
function is run and stored in a subtotal variable
on line 10. I will run this code and enter the two
dollar amounts called for in the input statements.
Notice the result. The print statement runs,
but the total does not show because the only
code in the calculate_total function is in the
pass statement. The benefit of having the pass
statement here is that, within this code, we can
still test the functionality of the get_amounts
function. At the same time, we await the
information needed to finish the calculate_total
function, which will save time for later testing
of this code, as we now know one function works as
expected. We have come to the end of the section
on functions. That means it’s time to analyze a
block of code and answer some questions about the
code. Look over the 425-analyze code and then
answer the questions in the workbook project
Review 4.2. I encourage you to enter this code
into a code editor and then run the code to help
answer the questions in the review exercise. We
will go through the answers in the next video.